Guide to the Maritime History Collection PR 100
© 2011 New-York Historical Society
Maritime History Collection
ca 1700 -- ca. 1960
PR 100
© 2011 New-York Historical Society
78.0 Linear feet (20 boxes, 130 flat files)
This collection is comprised of prints and photographs dealing with naval and maritime subjects, including naval engagements and portraits of ships and naval officers, most notably Captain James Lawrence and John Paul Jones.
Arrangement note
The materials have been arranged by size into four series. Within each series, materials are arranged by subject.
Provenance
The Maritime History Collection contains material collected from several sources. The bulk of the collection was a gift of The Naval History Society, John S. Barnes Foundation, 1925. Additional material arrived from Eugene H. Pool II, in a series of donations from 1941 to 1944. The remaining pieces were added to the collection by past staff members, when the subject matter related to maritime history.
Scope and Contents note
The Maritime History File spans the period from ca. 1700 – ca. 1960 and primarily contains prints and photographs relating to both naval and civilian maritime history. Not strictly a visual image collection, there are newspaper clippings, correspondence and various ephemera that add to the collection’s research value. The collection is divided into four series by size: Boxed Files holds material smaller than 9 x 14 inches; Medium Format Flat Files holds items between 9 x 14 and 24 x 40 inches; Large Format Flat Files holds material between 24 x 40 and 30 x 40 inches; and Oversize Format Flat Files holds material larger than 30 x 40 inches.
More detailed information about the contents is provided in the Scope and Contents notes for individual series and folders.
Historical note
The importance of New York as a port city is reflected in the large selection of naval and maritime prints found in this collection. Hundreds of prints from the Naval History Society’s John S. Barnes Memorial Library portray naval engagements, and also include portraits of ships and naval officers. The Eugene H. Pool collection contributed nearly 50 images related to Captain James Lawrence, and a large number of prints relate to John Paul Jones. Images of non-naval vessels include many portraits of individual trans-oceanic, coastal, and inland steamboats, yachts, and harbor craft.
- Series I. Boxed Files
  Scope and Contents note
  Series I. Boxed Files is comprised of material that is smaller than 9 x 14 inches and is housed in document boxes. Images are arranged by subject, with ships organized by type, then, when needed ordered alphabetically by name of person or ship. Files contain photographs, including carte-de-visites, cyanotypes, cabinet cards, prints, postcards, newspaper and magazine clipppings, reproductions of paintings and original drawings.
  - Subseries I.1: Sailing Vessels
    Sailing Vessels contains images of civilian ships that are powered only by wind, including clipper ships, cutters, Chinese junks, packet ships, schooners, and yachts. The images are arranged alphabetically by each vessel's name. Unidentified ships are sorted by medium and located after identified ships. Images of replicas of historically significant ships can be found in this group, including photographs of the Viking ship Lief Erikson, images of the Half Moon, built for the Hudson-Fulton Celebration in 1909 and photographs, including cyanotypes, of the Santa Maria, created for the 1893 World's Columbian Exposition.
    Related Archival Materials note
    See also: Box 17- Misc. Ships
    - A-C, 1900-1980 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Includes images of the Bluenose, Adelia T. Carleton, the Bark Aloha, the pilot boat America, the yacht America, the brig Aspasia, Aurora, the Red star packet Birmingham, USS Brandywine, the clipper ship Challenge, Charlemagne, the old whaler Charles W. Morgan, the revenue cutter Chase, the City of Mobile, the Columbia, Courier, the clipper bark Grapeshot and Cutty Sark.
    - D-G (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Includes images of the Dauntless, David Crockett, Defender, the sloop Dewitt Clinton, Dove, Edward Sewall, Fidelia, The Flying Cloud, the schooner Frank Atwood, Galatea, General Armstrong, G.W. Rosevelt, the clipper ship Glory of the Sea, the sloop Gjoa, S.S. Golden Gate and the clipper ship M.P. Grace.
    - Dreadnought (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Great Republic (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - H-M (Box 1, Folder 5)
      Includes images of the Havre, the packet ship Hercules, packet ship Isaac Webb, James Baines, Joseph Conrad, Joshua Bates, Flying Cloud, King Philip, Keying, La Duchesse D’Orleans, the bark Lagoda, Leif Erikson, Liberdade, Liverpool, E.R. Stirling, Barquentine Madalan, Barque Magdalene Vinnen, cutter yacht Maria, Mary Celeste, clipper barque Mermaid, Mirth, USS Monongahela and Moses Kimball.
    - Half Moon (Halve Maen) (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Mayflower (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - N-R (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Includes images of the clipper ship Nightingale, Niobe, Northern Light, Old Jersey, the clipper ship Oriental, Palma, Pamir, the schooner Brina P. Pendleton, Queen Mab, the clipper ship Racer, the clipper ship Rainbow, the clipper ship Red Jacket, Reliance and the clipper ship R.L. Lane.
    - S-Z (Box 1, Folder 9)
      Includes images of the brig Samaritano, the packet ship Samuel Lawrence, Sappho, the schooner Sinaloa, Sovereign of the Seas, Stag Hound, Thingvalla, Timandra, Tusitala, Ulysses, Valkyrie III, the schooner yacht Valor, Vamarie, the passenger clipper Waimate, the red star packet William Byrnes, the clipper ship Young America and the clipper bark Zephyr.
    - Santa Maria (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Unidentified Prints and Paintings (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Unidentified Photographs (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Subseries I.2: Steamships
    Steamships is copmrised of steam powered vesssels as well as those powered by the combination of steam and sail. Ships include paddle steamers, mail steamers, Coast Guard cutters, freighters and ocean liners. Many Hudson River steamboats are represented in this sub series. Images show ships in harbor and at sea and include several images of fires, shipwrecks and other accidents. There are a number of photographs of steamship interiors, including the interiors of ocean liners Caledonia, Conte Di Savoia, Leviathan, Kroonland and Manhattan and steamboats Robert Fulton and Washington Irving. IMages are arranged alphabetically by ship name with unidentified ships filed at the end of the subseries.
    See also: Box 17- Misc. Steamships
    - A (Box 2, Folder 1)
      Includes images of the steamer Avalon, A.B. Valentine, Acadia, Adirondack, Adriatic, S.S. Alaska, Albion, Alcoa Pathfinder, Alexander Hamilton, Alfred Thomas, Alice Dean, Alida, the steam yacht Alva, America, S.S. America, Royal Mail steamship America, American Farmer, S.S. American Merchant, S.S.Ampala, Amy Hewes, Anna, Ansonia, S.S. Antilles, Aquitania, Royal Mail steamship Arabia, Arago, U.S. Mail steam ship Arctic, S.S. Arizona, Arrow, S.S. Asbury Park, Ashland, English Mail steamship Asia, United States Mail steamship Atlantic, S.S. William C. Atwater, Augusta Victoria, S.S. Aurania and the Austin.
    - Albany (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - B (Box 2, Folder 3)
      Includes images of the United States Mail steamship Baltic, White Star Line steamship Baltic, Bay State, the Coast Guard cutter Bear, Bear Mountain, Bear of Oakland, Belle, Bellemere, Benjamin B. Odell, Berkshire, Black Warrior, Bohemian, S.S. Boston City, S.S. Bremen, Bristol City and the White Star Mail steamer Britannic.
    - Brazil (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Bristol (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Ca-Ch (Box 2, Folder 6)
      Includes images of the Caledonia, California, Cambria, Camden, S.S. Campania, Canton, Cape May, R.M.S. Carpathia, Cetus, Champlain, S.S. Chattahoochee, Chonsu, S.S. Christopher Columbus, Charles A. Stafford, Chelsea and C.H. Northam.
    - RMS Caronia (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Chauncey M. DePew (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - C. Vibbard (Chauncey Vibbard) (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Ci (Box 2, Folder 10)
      Includes images of the City of Albany, City of Bangor, City of Boston, City of Detroit, City of Fall River, City of Grand Rapids, City of Holland, City of Hudson, City of Kingston, City of Norwich, City of Philadelphia, City of Rockland, S.S. City of Rome, City of San Francisco and City of Springfield.
    - City of New York (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Cl-Cz (Box 2, Folder 12)
      Includes images of the steamer Cleopatra, Columbia, S.S. Columbia, S.S. Columbian, Columbus, Commonwealth, Conquest, Conte di Savoia, Continental, La Corraine, Corsicana, C.P. Smith, Cumberland, C. Vanderbilt and Cygnus.
    - Clermont (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Connecticut (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - D (Box 3, Folder 1)
      Includes images of the Daniel Drew, Daniel Miller, Daniel Webster, Dean Richmond, Del Norte, Deutschland, S.S. Devonia, De Witt Clinton, Dolphin, Drew and Dunbar.
    - E (Box 3, Folder 2)
      Includes images of the steamer Eastern City, Eastern States, Ecuador, Edinburgh, Eliza Mancox, Elm City, El Paraguay, Emeline, Emerald, Empire of Troy, Empire State, Empress of Ireland, Erastus Corning, U.S.Training Ship Essex, S.S. Etruria, Eudora, S.S. Europa and Express.
    - F (Box 3, Folder 3)
      Includes images of the Fairfield, Falmouth, S.S. Flandre, Florence, Forest City, Fort Orange, France, Francis Skiddy, Frank E. Kirby, Franklin, S.S. Friesland, Frostburg, S.S. Fulda, Fulton and S.S. Furnessia.
    - G (Box 3, Folder 4)
      Includes images of the General Greene, General Lincoln,: Includes images of the Hampton, Harlem, S.S. Harry G. Coulby, Hartford, S.S. Harvard, Helka, Henry Clay, Henry E. Bishop, Henry W. Longfellow, Horatio Hall, Holmdel, Homer Ramsdell and Horicon. General Mosquera, General Price, General Sedgwicke, General Slocum, General Whitney, Georgia, Germanic, Golden Age, Goldenrod, Governor Dingley, Govenor Emerson C. Harrington, Grand Republic, Granite State, Great Eastern, Greater Detroit, Great Northern and Gulf Coast.
    - H (Box 3, Folder 5)
      Includes images of the Hampton, Harlem, S.S. Harry G. Coulby, Hartford, S.S. Harvard, Helka, Henry Clay, Henry E. Bishop, Henry W. Longfellow, Horatio Hall, Holmdel, Homer Ramsdell and Horicon.
    - Hendrick Hudson (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - I-J (Box 3, Folder 7)
      Includes images of the Idlewild, Ile de France, Imperator, I.N. Seymour, S.S. Independence, Iona, Iron Witch, Iroquois, Isabel, Island Home, Mohawk, James T. Brett, James Stevens, Jamestown, James W. Baldwin, James W. Wadsworth, J.M. White, John A. Meseck, John Brooks, John McCausland, John Romer, John Stevens, John Swasey, John Wesley, Joseph O. Osgood, J.S. Warden, J.T. Morse and the yacht Julia.
    - Isaac Newton (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - K (Box 3, Folder 9)
      Includes images of the Kaaterskill, S.S. Kaiser Wilhelm, Kansas, S.S. Kansas City, Katahdin, Kennebec, S.S. Kensington, Knickerbocker, S.S. Kronprinzessin Cecilie, Kroonland and Kurrachee.
    - L (Box 3, Folder 10)
      Includes images of the S.S. La Bretagne, Laconia, Lady of the Lake, L’Amerique, Larchmont, La Touraine, Leonardo Da Vinci, Lewiston, Liberte, Llandaff City, S.S. Lucania, Luckenbach Line, Lusitania and Lyman Truman.
    - Leviathan (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Lexington (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Ma (Box 4, Folder 1)
      Includes images of the Magenta, Magnolia, Maid-Kent, Maid of the Mist, Majestic, Maine, White Star line S.S. Majestic, S.S. Manhattan, Manitoba, Manitoulin, Marblehead, Mariposa, Mary Benton, Mary Patten, Matangas, Mauretania and the steamship Mayflower.
    - Mary Powell (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Massachusetts (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Me-Mz (Box 4, Folder 4)
      Includes images of R.M.S. Media, Memphis, Merchant, Merrimack, Meteor, Metropolis,U.S. Revenue Cutter Michigan, Middletown, Milwaukie, Minnie Cornell, Mississippi, M. Martin, S.S. Mobile, Mobjack, Mohawk, Monmouth, Montana, Moosehead, Morrisania and Myles Standish.
    - N (Box 4, Folder 5)
      Includes images of the Nahant, Nantasket, Nantucket, Nasookin, Natchez, Newport, New Orleans, New World, New York, S.S. New York, Nordstjernan, Nieuw Amsterdam, S.S. Normannia, North America, North Star, Northumberland, Norwich, Nutmeg State and Nymph.
    - Normandie (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - O (Box 4, Folder 7)
      Includes images of the Oakes Ames, S.S. Obdam, Oceanic, R.M.S. Oceanic, Octorara, S.S. Ohio, Old Dominion, Olive Branch, S.S. Olympic, Onteora, Oregon, S.S. Oriente and S.S. Otho.
    - Pa-Pl (Box 4, Folder 8)
      Includes images of the steamboat Paragon, S.S. Pan America, Parahyba, the steamship Paris, USS Pawnee, Pegasus, S.S. Pennsylvania, USS Pensacola, Peytona, Pheonix, Pere Marouette, S.S. Peter Stuyvesant, Pilgrim Belle, Pleasure Bay and Plymouth.
    - Pilgrim (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Po-Pz (Box 4, Folder 10)
      Includes images of the Polaris, Pomona, Portland, Potomac, President, S.S. President Coolidge, Prince George, Princess Louise, Princess Mary, US Steamer Princeton, Prinzessin Victoria Luise, Priscilla and Providence.
    - Puritan (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Q-R (Box 4, Folder 12)
      Includes images of the Quaker, USS Quaker City, RMS Queen Elizabeth, RMS Queen Elizabeth II, Quinnebaug, Quonset, Ramona, S.S. Randwijk, Red Jacket (original drawing), S.S. Regina, Reindeer, Rembrandt, Republic, Rhode-Island, Richard Stockton, Richelieu, Rip Vanwinkle, River Queen, S.S. Roanoke, Robert A. Snyder, Robert E. Lee, Rochester, Roosevelt, Rosedale, Ross Winans, S.S. Rotterdam and Cunard steamship Russia.
    - Queen Mary (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Robert Fulton (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Sa-Sb (Box 5, Folder 1)
      Includes images of the S.S. Saale, Sagamore, Saguenay, St. Croix, St. Johns, St. John, St. Lawrence, St. Louis, Sam Sloan, Sandy Hook, San Francisco, Sankaty, San Miguel, Santa Barbara, Santa Inez, Santa Clara, Santa Maria, Southward Bound, Sapphire, Saturn and Saxonia.
    - Santa Rosa (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Savannah (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Sc-Sz (Box 5, Folder 4)
      Includes images of the S.S. Schiedyk, Sea Bird, Seawanhaka, Secaucus, Selma Victory, S.S. Servia, Shady Side, Shamrock, Shinnecock, Signal, Sirius, Smithfield, South American, Spartan, Stad Luzern, State of Maine, Storm King, Sunnyside, S.S. Sussex, Swallow and Sylvan Dell.
    - Statendam (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - T (Box 5, Folder 6)
      Includes images of the Tashmoo, Taurus Commodore, T.D. Wilcox, Telegraph, Teutonic, Thebes, Thomas Clyde, Thomas Cornell, Thomas Patten, Thomas Powell, S.S. Tillie Lykes, Trenton, Titanic, Trenton, S.S. Trinidad, Twilight, T.V. Arrowsmith,Toltec and Trojan.
    - Ticonderoga (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - U-V (Box 5, Folder 8)
      Includes images of the S.S. Ulua, S.S. Umbira, Union, United Empire, S.S. United States, Vaderland, Vanderbilt, Venezuela, S.S. Veragua, Victoria, Packet-boat Vienna, Vigilant, US Mail steamer Virginia, Volendam and S.S. Vulcania.
    - W-Z (Box 5, Folder 9)
      Includes images of the Walter Brett, Walk-in-the-Water, Warwick, Washington Irving, S.S. Werra, Westerdyk, Westernland, Western World, Westport, William F. Romer, William Jenkins, W.M. Harrison, William Norris, Wyoming, Yale and Yankee.
    - Washington (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Early Stem Vessels (incl. Robert Fulton's) (Box 5, Folder 11)
      Includes images of early steamboats including those designed by James Rumsey, John Fitch and Robert Fulton.
    - Misc.-Multiple Ships (Box 5, Folder 12)
      Includes images of the Chauncey M.Depew, Chaperon, Springfield, City of Keansburg, Elizabeth Monroe Smith, Bombay, Meta and Whaleback Steamers.
    - Unidentified Prints (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Unidentified Photographs (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Steamships, A-Z and Unidentified (small format photographs), Albumen Print (Box 16)
  - Subseries I.3: Naval Ships & Equipment
    Naval Ships & Equipment contains images of a variety of naval vessels including battleships, cruisers, destryoers, frigates, monitors, navy hospital ships, torpedo boats, and so on. United States naval ships comprise the majority of these images, but a group of foreign naval vessels can be found at the end of the subseries. The USS Maine, both before and after its destruction, and the USS Constitution are well represented. Photographs of the United States Pacific Fleet traveling through the Panama Canal in 1919 are filed under individual ship name as well as under "Numbered Destroyers." Images by photographers J.S. Johnston and the Pach Brothers (USS Brooklyn, USS New York, USS Oregon, USS Texas) are found throughout this subseries.
    See also: Boxes 16 & 17- Columbian Naval Review
    - A-B (Box 6, Folder 1)
      Includes images of the U.S.S. Abner Reed, U.S.S. Alaska, U.S. Cruiser Albany, U.S.S. Alfred, Frigate Alliance, U.S.S. Alywin, S.S. American Farmer, U.S.S. Ammen, U.S.S. Amphitrite, U.S.S. Antares, U.S.S. Argonne, U.S.S. Arizona, U.S.S. Atlanta, U.S. Cruiser Atlanta, U.S.S. Augusta, U.S.S. Augusta, U.S.S. Bagley, U.S. Cruiser Baltimore, U.S.S. Bancroft, U.S.S. Basswood, U.S.S. Beale, U.S.S. Benevolence, U.S.S. Benham, U.S.S. Benson, U.S.S. Beukesdijk, U.S.N. Bennington, U.S.S. Birmingham, the flag ship Blackhawk, U.S.S. Bobolink, U.S.S. Boise and U.S.S. Brooks.
    - USS Alabama (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - USS Anderson (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - USS Arkansas (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - USS Boston (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - USS Brooklyn (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - C-D (Box 6, Folder 7)
      Includes images of the U.S.S. California, U.S.S. Carondelet, U.S.S. Case, U.S.S. Charleston, U.S. Cruiser Charleston, U.S.S. Chester, U.S.S. Cincinnati, U.S.S. Colorado, U.S. Torpedo Boat Cushing, U.S.N Cushing, U.S.S. Davis, U.S.S. Delaware, New Destroyer Escort DE 13 (U.S.S. Brennan), U.S.S. Despatch, U.S.S. Detroit, U.S.S. Dewey, U.S.S. Dictator, U.S.S. Dixie, U.S. Dispatch Boat Dolphin, U.S.S. Drayton, U.S.S. Drexler and U.S.S. Dunlap.
    - USS Chicago (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - USS Columbia (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - USS Concord (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - USS Constellation (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - USS Constitution (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - E-G (Box 6, Folder 13)
      Includes images of the U.S.S. Eagle, TS Empire State, U.S.S. Ericsson, U.S.S. Erie, U.S. Frigate Essex, U.S.S. Falcon, U.S.S. Farragut, U.S.S. Finch, U.S.S. Frolic, U.S. Steam Frigate Fulton, U.S.S. Galena, U.S.S. Gansevoort, U.S.C.G. George W. Campbell, U.S.S. Gleaves, U.S.S. Goodrich, U.S.S. Governor Moore, Grand Turk, Great Republic, U.S.S. Granite State and U.S.S. Gridley.
    - USS Enterprise (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - H-L (Box 6, Folder 15)
      Includes images of the U.S. Frigate Hancock, U.S.S. Hartford, U.S.S. Hatfield, U.S.S. Hawk, U.S.S. Henderson, U.S.S. Hobby, U.S.S. Holland, U.S.S. Honolulu, U.S.S. Hornet, U.S.S. Houston, U.S. Steam Sloop of War Housatonic, U.S.S. Idaho, U.S.S. Illinois, U.S.S. Independence, U.S.S. Indianapolis, U.S.S. James K. Paulding, U.S.S. Jamestown, U.S.S. Jason, U.S.S. Kane, U.S.S. Katahdin, U.S.S. Kendrich, U.S. Battleship Kentucky, U.S. Ironclad Keokuk, U.S.S. Kittery, U.S.S. Lancaster, U.S.S. Lexington and U.S.S. Leyden.
    - USS Indiana (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - USS Iowa (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - USS J. William Ditter (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - USS Kearsage (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - M (Box 7, Folder 1)
      Includes images of the U.S.S. Macdonough, U.S.S. Mahan, U.S.S. Mahopac, U.S.S. Maury, U.S. Destroyer McCall, U.S.S. Medusa, U.S.S. Memphis, U.S. Steam Frigate Merrimac, U.S.S. Michigan, U.S.S. Milwaukee, U.S. Steam Frigate Gibraltar, U.S.S. Missouri, U.S.S. Monitor, U.S.S. Monongahela, U.S. Cruiser Montgomery, U.S.S. Monticello, U.S.S. Morris and U.S.S. Mullany.
    - USS Maine (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - USS Massachusetts (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - USS Miantonoma (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - USS Minneapolis (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - USS Mississippi (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - N-O (Box 7, Folder 7)
      Includes images of the U.S.S. Nebraska, U.S.S. Nevada, U.S.S. Newark, U.S.S. New Hampshire, U.S.S. New Jersey, U.S.S. New Orleans, U.S.S. Nicholas, U.S.S. Oahu, U.S.S. Ohio, U.S.S. Oklahoma and U.S.S. Onondaga.
    - USS New Ironsides (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - USS New Mexico (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - USS New York (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - USS North Carolina (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - USS Olympia (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - USS Oregon (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - P (Box 7, Folder 14)
      Includes images of the C.S.S. Palmetto State, U.S.S. Palos, U.S.S. Passaic, U.S.S. Petrel, U.S.S. Phelps, U.S.S. Philadelphia, U.S. Revenue Cutter Pickering, U.S.S. Pigeon, U.S.S. Pompano, U.S. Brig Porpoise, U.S. Torpedo Boat Porter, U.S.S. Portsmouth, U.S.S. Powhatan, U.S.S Prairie, U.S.S. President and P.T. 105.
    - USS Pennsylvania (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - USS Philadelphia (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Q-R (Box 7, Folder 17)
      Includes images of the U.S.S. Quinnebaug, U.S.S. Rail, U.S.S. Raleigh, U.S.S. Ramsay, U.S.S. Randolph, U.S.S. Red Rover, U.S.S. Reid, U.S.S. Relief, U.S.S. Repose and U.S.S. Richmond.
    - USS Ranger (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - USS Rhode Island (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - S-U (Box 8, Folder 1)
      Includes images of the U.S. Frigate Sabine, U.S.S. Sacramento, U.S.S. Salt Lake City, U.S.S. St. Louis, U.S.S. St. Mary, H.M.S. Shannon, U.S.N. San Francisco, U.S.S. San Marcos, U.S.S. Santiago de Cuba, U.S.S. Savannah, U.S.S. Seal, USRC Seminole, U.S.S. Sirius, U.S.S. Somers, U.S.S. Spuyten Duyvil, C.S.S. Stonewall Jackson, U.S.S. Sylph, U.S.S. Talbot, U.S.S. Tarpon, U.S.S. Teal, U.S.S. Tennessee, U.S.S. Tern, U.S. Monitor Terror, U.S.S. Trenton and U.S.S. Tuscaloosa.
    - USS Saratoga (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - USS Texas (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - USS United States (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - V-Z (Box 8, Folder 5)
      Includes images of the U.S.S. Vandalia, U.S.S. Vermont, U.S.S. Villalobos, U.S.S. Vincennes, U.S.S. Vesuvius, C.S.S. Virginia, U.S. Steam Frigate Wabash, U.S.S. Warrington, U.S.S. Washington, U.S.S. West Virginia, U.S.S. Wilmington, U.S.S. Winslow, U.S.S. Wisconsin, U.S.S. Yantic, U.S.S. Yorktown and U.S.S. Yosemite.
    - USS Vesuvius (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - USS Wyoming (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Numbered Destroyers (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Submarines, Submarine Chasers & Rams (Box 8, Folder 9)
      Includes images of the Deutschland, Bushnell’s Turtle, U.S.S. Nautilus, U.S.S. Narwhal, U.S.S. Holland, U.S.S. Barracuda, U.S.S. S-50 and S-51, U.S.S. Tarpon, U.S.S. Viper, S-26, U.S.S. Argonaut, U.S.S. Bass, U.S.S. Plunger, U-58, S-29, U.S. Subchaser 39, U.S. Subchaser 49 and U.S.S. Katahdin.
    - Misc. Foreign Naval Ships (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - British Naval Ships (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - HMS Renown (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - HMS Victory (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Dutch Naval Ships (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - French Naval Ships (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - German Naval Ships (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Italian Naval Ships (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Japanese Naval Ships (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Spanish Naval Ships (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Multiple Ships- Misc. (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Unidentified Naval Ships (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Naval & Coast Guard Aircraft (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Naval Ships [possibly at the Columbian Naval Review] (Box 17)
    - Naval Vessels, A-B (American Book Company photographs) (Box 18, Folder 1)
      Includes images of U.S.N. Atlanta, the Cruiser Baltimore and the Cruiser Bennington
    - Naval Vessels, C-F (American Book Company photographs) (Box 18, Folder 2)
      Includes images of U.S.N. Chicago, U.S.N. Cincinnati, U.S.N. Cushing, Torpedo Boat Ericsson and the Battleship Florida.
    - Naval Vessels, I-P (American Book Company photographs) (Box 18, Folder 3)
      Includes images of U.S.N. Indiana, U.S.S. Monterey and U.S.N. Petrel.
    - Naval Vessels, T-Y (American Book Company photographs) (Box 18, Folder 4)
      Includes images of Battleship Texas U.S.N., Vesuvius U.S.N and Yorktown U.S.N.
  - Subseries I.4: Other Ships & Ship Details